A very popular strategy for gambling used
إحدى الاستراتيجيات المشهورة جداً في المقامرة
with Roulette and other games is called the Martingale strategy.
وتُستخدم في لعبة الروليت وألعاب أخرى، تُدعى استراتيجية Martingale.
You start betting small and every time you lose,
تبدأ فيها بالرهان بمبالغ صغيرة، وكلما تخسر،
you play again betting double as much as the previous bet.
تلعب مجدداً وتراهن بضعف المبلغ الذي راهنت به سابقاً.
And when you actually win you make up for all the losses you've
وعندما تفوز فعلاً، ستعوض جميع خساراتك
suffered so far plus a small profit thanks to that double bet strategy.
التي تكبدتها حتى الآن، بالإضافة إلى ربح بسيط بفضل استراتيجية الرهان المضاعف.
Which means you can now reset your bet back to
ما يعني أنه يمكنك الآن إعادة تعيين قيمة رهانك
that small starting bet and start all over again.
إلى تلك القيمة الأولية الصغيرة، والبدء من جديد.
This strategy assumes that you would eventually
تفترض هذه الاستراتيجية أنك في النهاية
build up all those small profits over time.
ستكوم جميع تلك الأرباح الصغيرة مع مرور الوقت.
But the danger is that you could easily run out of money.
لكن الخطر يكمن في إمكانية نفاد نقودك بسهولة،
Because you're doubling your bet every time,
لأنك تضاعف رهانك في كل مرة،
money would run out real fast.
ستنفد النقود بسرعة كبيرة.
The key now is to know when to stop.
الأمر المهم هو معرفة متى عليك أن تتوقف.
Let's assume you're going to start with
لنفترض أنك ستبدأ بألف دولار،
meaning that you would end up with $12,000.
ما يعني أنه سيصبح معك 1200 دولار في النهاية.
However, the minimum bet that you can play is $10.
لكن أدنى مبلغ يمكنك المراهنة به هو 10 دولارات.
So to get there, you start with this minimum bet of
لتحقيق ذلك، ستبدأ المراهنة بالمبلغ الأدنى وهو 10 دولارات،
$10 and you would keep doubling every time you lose,
وستستمر في مضاعفته كلما تخسر.
but reset it back to 10 once you win.
لكنك ستعيد المراهنة من جديد بـ10 دولارات حالما تفوز.
Here's the function called martingale.
ها هي الدالة التي تسمى martingale.
It doesn't have any input parameters,
ليس لديها معلمتين للمدخلات،
but it returns the integer,
لكنها تعرض العدد الحقيقي،
which is the value of the money you end up with,
وهو قيمة النقود التي تحصل عليها في النهاية،
which could be either more than what you started with or a lot less.
ويمكن أن تكون أكثر من المال الذي بدأت به أو أقل منه بكثير.
The first thing we do is we start with initializing those three variables here: money,
أول شيء نفعله هو أننا نبدأ بتعيين قيم أولية للمتغيرات الثلاثة هنا: money
target and bet, equal to those values.
وtarget وbet، ونجعلها مساوية لتلك القيم.
And then we have this while loop.
ثم لدينا حلقة while هذه.
The idea of this loop is that it would keep repeating this code block down
فكرة هذه الحلقة هي أنها ستستمر في تكرار كتلة التعليمات البرمجية هذه في الأسفل هنا
here for as long as we still have enough money to place a bet.
طالما أننا نملك ما يكفي من النقود للرهان.
So as long as money is greater than bet.
إذن طالما أن money&gt;bet.
Once we don't have enough money anymore,
حالما لا يكون معنا ما يكفي من النقود،
then we just return whatever money we have.
سنعرض أياً كان مبلغ المال الذي لدينا كنتيجة.
Inside that loop, we're using this function called play.
نستخدم داخل تلك الحلقة دالة تسمى play.
This function simulates the actual betting game play.
تحاكي هذه الدالة عملية الرهان الفعلية.
Assume it's implemented somewhere else and it returns a boolean.
افترض أنه تم تطبيقها في مكان آخر وعرضت تعبيراً منطقياً.
This boolean is true if you've won that bet and false if you didn't.
تكون قيمة التعبير المنطقي هذا true إن فزت بالرهان، وfalse إن خسرت.
So we're storing the return value of this function into the variable win here,
إذن، نحفظ قيمة ناتج هذه الدالة في متغير win هنا،
which is a boolean, and we're checking if we actually did win this bet or not.
وهو متغير منطقي، ونتفحص ما إن فزنا حقاً أم لا.
If we did, we just add the bet value to our money and then reset it back to 10.
إن فزنا، سنضيف فقط قيمة bet إلى money ونعيد تعيين القيمة إلى 10.
If we didn't win this bet,
وإن لم نفز بالرهان،
we subtract it from our money value and then we
فسنطرح قيمته من قيمة money
multiply the actual bet by two so that we double the bet for the next time.
ثم نضرب الرهان الفعلي باثنان لمضاعفة الرهان للمرة القامة.
This code block here would keep repeating
ستستمر كتلة التعليمات البرمجية هذه بالتكرار
until we don't have enough money to bet anymore.
حتى لا يبقى معنا نقود كافية للرهان.
Now there is one part missing here.
هناك جزء مفقود هنا.
We need to break out of this loop when it's time to stop
علينا الخروج من هذه الحلقة عندما يحين الوقت للتوقف عن اللعب،
playing and that's when we've reached our target that we're happy with.
ويحدث ذلك عندما نصل إلى هدفنا الذي سنسعد به.
Modify this code here by adding an IF condition that
عدّل الكود هذا عبر إضافة عبارة if
checks if the money has reached or exceeded our predefined target.
تتفحص ما إن وصلت النقود، money، هدفنا المحدد مسبقاً أو تعدّته.
And if so, break from this loop.
إن كانت تلك هي الحال، اخرج من هذه الحلقة.